<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Crazyc4t&#39;s Home</title>
    <link>http://saidneder.tech/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Crazyc4t&#39;s Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 20:59:45 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://saidneder.tech/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What to do after installing Fedora KDE</title>
      <link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/debloating_fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 20:59:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/debloating_fedora/</guid>
      
        <description>Welcome again to my blog, it has been a bit of a long time isn&amp;rsquo;t it? But am back once again!</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim for everyone!</title>
      <link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/vimforeveryone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 22:00:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/vimforeveryone/</guid>
      
        <description>Intro This is a vim-neovim tutorial, is a highly-configurable text editor that you can make it as you wish, and the way to use it is only with the keyboard and keybindings and learning it will improve your productivity at a whole other level, and it is included in every UNIX system and Mac OS, so if you configure servers remotely or work a lot in the terminal is really important to use vim, and you can add plugins and make a lot of cool stuff with it!</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to free yourself by installing linux</title>
      <link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/freeyourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 01:40:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/freeyourself/</guid>
      
        <description>Intro This is a special blogpost since this is the guide to switch from windows to linux for new users, and the way to free them of propietary software and enjoy their freedom with free software, the software you should run!</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to customize your terminal!</title>
      <link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/niceterminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 19:55:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/niceterminal/</guid>
      
        <description>Intro This is a tutorial-type of blogpost, sorry for being away so long, but there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of blogposts coming to your way, so expect some new ones!</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is GNU &#43; Linux? Why should you care?</title>
      <link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/penguin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 18:58:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/penguin/</guid>
      
        <description>Intro Am going to talk about one of my favourite things in the world, what lead me to where I am today, Linux, the open-source operating system created by the community!</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>