<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on crazyc4t</title><link>https://crazyc4t.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on crazyc4t</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 13:55:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://crazyc4t.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to comeback and win in life</title><link>https://crazyc4t.github.io/posts/comeback/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 23:53:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://crazyc4t.github.io/posts/comeback/</guid><description>First of all, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the definition of the word comeback shall we?
Comeback: a return to a former higher rank, popularity, position, prosperity, etc.
With that being said, a comeback is when you are on the low side of your streak and you make the effort to get back where you deserve and were.</description></item><item><title>What is Linux? Why should you care?</title><link>https://crazyc4t.github.io/posts/linuxforn00bs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 18:58:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://crazyc4t.github.io/posts/linuxforn00bs/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s answer the first question first&amp;hellip;
What is linux? You use Linux everyday, without even noticing, you are using linux right now!! since this webpage is hosted on github, and github is hosted on azure that is the cloud computing service that microsoft offers, that their servers are based on linux, you see the connection?</description></item><item><title>Why minimalism is important in your life</title><link>https://crazyc4t.github.io/posts/minimalism/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 23:13:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://crazyc4t.github.io/posts/minimalism/</guid><description>This is my first (and not last) blogpost talking about life advice and my opinions so just buckle up and enjoy the ride!
What is minimalism in the first place? Is really self-explanatory isn&amp;rsquo;t it?</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://crazyc4t.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 10:20:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://crazyc4t.github.io/about/</guid><description>Am Said Neder, a 17 year old ecuadorian, a free software enthusiast who loves programming, better said, technology altogether, and I found that of myself when I was 15 years old and the covid pandemic striked in, and I was stuck at home, for a complete year, and for me that time where I was completely alone because my older brother that is like my best friend left, I was just with my parents, and then I knew that it was my time to shine, I have always admired people that were very technical with computers and the sexy looking terminals in the hacker movies made me really interested, so I picked up python to learn while being at home, and it was one of the best decisions of my life, I had so much fun to learn to have the power of doing everything that I wanted to create, and the constant learning that made me excited for every new topic, but that was like 2 years ago.</description></item></channel></rss>