<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Crazyc4t's Home</title><link>http://saidneder.tech/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Crazyc4t's Home</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 13:55:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://saidneder.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I passed the compTIA A+</title><link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/a+/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 12:10:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/a+/</guid><description>Guide to conquer compTIA A+ This is the guide to conquer compTIA A+ made by Said Neder, this is what am doing to study and get certified!</description></item><item><title>What to do after installing Fedora KDE</title><link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/debloating_fedora/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 20:59:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/debloating_fedora/</guid><description>Welcome again to my blog, it has been a bit of a long time isn&amp;rsquo;t it? But am back once again!</description></item><item><title>How to write your own discord bot!</title><link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/discordbot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 11:19:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/discordbot/</guid><description>Patrick Star Bot 📕 This is my first time programming a bot on discord with discord.js! This bot is about having my classes at my fingertips, so it gives links with special commands that facilitate the process.</description></item><item><title>LaTeX for humans</title><link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/latexforhumans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 17:22:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/latexforhumans/</guid><description>Intro This post is going to help you learn \(\LaTeX\) and convert you into a intellectual and scientific professional and by far superior with anyone that shares their report made in word!</description></item><item><title>How can overthinking ruin your mindset</title><link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/dontoverthink/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 01:56:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/dontoverthink/</guid><description>Intro Well first let me welcome you to this new year 2022! I wish you the best for this year and time to rock on and create and achieve what you most want!</description></item><item><title>Vim for everyone!</title><link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/vimforeveryone/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 22:00:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/vimforeveryone/</guid><description>Intro This is a vim-neovim tutorial, is a highly-configurable text editor that you can make it as you wish, and the way to use it is only with the keyboard and keybindings and learning it will improve your productivity at a whole other level, and it is included in every UNIX system and Mac OS, so if you configure servers remotely or work a lot in the terminal is really important to use vim, and you can add plugins and make a lot of cool stuff with it!</description></item><item><title>How to free yourself by installing linux</title><link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/freeyourself/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 01:40:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/freeyourself/</guid><description>Intro This is a special blogpost since this is the guide to switch from windows to linux for new users, and the way to free them of propietary software and enjoy their freedom with free software, the software you should run!</description></item><item><title>How to customize your terminal!</title><link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/niceterminal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 19:55:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/niceterminal/</guid><description>Intro This is a tutorial-type of blogpost, sorry for being away so long, but there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of blogposts coming to your way, so expect some new ones!</description></item><item><title>How to comeback and win in life</title><link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/comeback/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 23:53:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/comeback/</guid><description>Intro First of all, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the definition of the word comeback shall we?
Comeback: a return to a former higher rank, popularity, position, prosperity, etc.</description></item><item><title>What is GNU + Linux? Why should you care?</title><link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/penguin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 18:58:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/penguin/</guid><description>Intro Am going to talk about one of my favourite things in the world, what lead me to where I am today, Linux, the open-source operating system created by the community!</description></item><item><title>Why minimalism is important in your life</title><link>http://saidneder.tech/blog/minimalism/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 23:13:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://saidneder.tech/blog/minimalism/</guid><description>Intro This is my first (and not last) blogpost talking about life advice and my opinions so just buckle up and enjoy the ride!</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>http://saidneder.tech/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 10:20:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://saidneder.tech/about/</guid><description>Am Said Neder, a 17 year old ecuadorian, a free software enthusiast who loves programming, better said, technology altogether, and I found that of myself when I was 15 years old and the covid pandemic striked in, and I was stuck at home, for a complete year, and for me that time where I was completely alone because my older brother that is like my best friend left, I was just with my parents, and then I knew that it was my time to shine, I have always admired people that were very technical with computers and the sexy looking terminals in the hacker movies made me really interested, so I picked up python to learn while being at home, and it was one of the best decisions of my life, I had so much fun to learn to have the power of doing everything that I wanted to create, and the constant learning that made me excited for every new topic, but that was like 2 years ago.</description></item></channel></rss>