<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Advice on crazyc4t's blog</title><link>https://saidneder.tech/tags/advice/</link><description>Recent content in Advice on crazyc4t's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 01:56:57 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saidneder.tech/tags/advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How can overthinking ruin your mindset</title><link>https://saidneder.tech/blog/dontoverthink/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 01:56:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://saidneder.tech/blog/dontoverthink/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://saidneder.tech/images/chill-images/ba%C3%B1os.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post How can overthinking ruin your mindset" />&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Well first let me welcome you to this new year 2022! I wish you the best for this year and time to rock on and create and achieve what you most want! I welcome you to this new year with this new blog post! I haven&amp;rsquo;t write an advice post in a while so let&amp;rsquo;s get started!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-overthinking">What is overthinking?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Overthinking is just the action to before doing something you think a lot of that action so you can excuse yourself to not do it, If you need to training, but before showering and getting ready you are already thinking &amp;ldquo;My pinky toe hurts a bit I should stay&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; just getting excuses on top of your head to not do something that you don&amp;rsquo;t feel like doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-can-it-ruin-your-mindset">How can it ruin your mindset?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Your mindset being the way you think, to make an action and make it your way, the way you tackle things and situations in life, how do you feel if something happens, this ruins your mindset completly in the way that if something bad happens, for example you are trying to leave tobacco and you smoke a cigarette and relapse, how do you feel about it? The first thought is regret, and then the following thought is a strategy to leave it, but then you overthink it, while you think about it you are seeing the difficulty of it, the struggle you will have to pass, and that makes you thing to go out with a &amp;ldquo;blast&amp;rdquo; and so you light up another cigarette and say &amp;ldquo;this one is for good, my goodbye one&amp;rdquo; and cycles repeats.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But why? Because you didn&amp;rsquo;t took action when you supposed to, the second thought being the strategy to leave tobacco, should be as easy as saying &amp;ldquo;I will not smoke tobacco anymore&amp;rdquo; and go on with your day, but instead you thought about what if, what am going to do if, and so on and so forth that you think that is too hard and just to not feel bad you light up another cigarette&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-can-we-stop-overthinking">How can we stop overthinking?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Is not easy, is a fight am going through a lot right now, but I can share some tips:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Develop a &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; theory
That being that every opportunity that you have to do something different, or a thought that came to your mind to cook something or just something you wanna do, just say &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo;, and do it right away, don&amp;rsquo;t think about tasks that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to do, everytime you want to do something just say yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Meditate
This is pretty self-explanatory, try to take some time of your day to meditate, could be in the shower, after having some exercise, as you wish, but take some time to think how you are going through the day, what you need to improve and essentially to take it with calm and with wisedom.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Read a book
This certainly will teach you to not think twice, since reading a book is boring and difficult and you always put excuses for it, just grab it and read 5 pages, and that way you will develop an habit to just do what you need and want to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Develop the right mindset
Be positive, notice your progress, be happy about it, listen to good music and enjoy the life that you have since there could be no tomorrow so enjoy it as it fullest, and don&amp;rsquo;t let a little slip-up ruin your whole day, get the right mindset, know your goals, be honest with yourself and know what are you doing great and what you are not, make a plan and improve.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Clean your room everyday
Everyday clean your room, your desk, mop the floor, tidy everything up, organize your things and develop the habit to do it every morning, it will make you feel good to go on with your other tasks.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="outro">Outro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This are my 2 cents, I write this advices to myself but I know someone could need this and that&amp;rsquo;s why I share them with you, if you know something and you don&amp;rsquo;t share it, that&amp;rsquo;s just being selfish right? hope you liked this post and I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you updated!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to comeback and win in life</title><link>https://saidneder.tech/blog/comeback/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 23:53:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://saidneder.tech/blog/comeback/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://saidneder.tech/images/chill-images/cuicocha.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post How to comeback and win in life" />&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>First of all, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the definition of the word &lt;strong>comeback&lt;/strong> shall we?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Comeback: a return to a former higher rank, popularity, position, prosperity, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>With that being said, a comeback is when you are on the low side of your streak and you make
the effort to get back where you deserve and were.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is critical in life, you will have a lot of situations that will demotivate you,
stop your momentum, your rhythm, and make you begin from scratch again,
and it will be difficult, to not say painful, since from your growth zone you fell back
to your comfort zone, and then is when you have to get &lt;strong>up.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You first need to organize yourself and create a plan of &lt;strong>attack&lt;/strong>, since this is a
problem needed to be taken with aggression.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="plan-of-attack">Plan of attack&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>First of all you &lt;strong>should have a journal&lt;/strong>, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have one, don&amp;rsquo;t worry about it,
(Tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s post will be how to journal and document your day to day so don&amp;rsquo;t forget!)
but before we need to answer this:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Why a journal?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Because in a journal you document what you do in your day to day, so if you feel something is not going as planned,
or you feel like you are not better that yesterday, go and check what you did and your thoughts of that day and compare them
with your thoughts of today or the day that wasn&amp;rsquo;t that good, and the next day try to mimic the same thoughts, and activities,
to gain momentum, I know that is hard and that advice is a bit stupid &amp;ldquo;if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to do something, just do it and that&amp;rsquo;s it&amp;rdquo;,
but there is where the plan of attack comes into place, this is a war between you and yourself, so you have to know yourself where
to attack, your weakest points, your good points, where you can get attacked, and how to defend yourself, &lt;strong>you vs you&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="organization">Organization&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Organize your day wisely, because this is what will change the outcome, the first hour of your day is extremly important,
you can&amp;rsquo;t screw this up, if you screw the first hour of your day, it will be really difficult to come back on top,
so organize your day from the less stimulating activity to the most, from the less difficult to the hardest one, for example:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Wake up&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Take a shower&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tidy up your room&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Document your journal &lt;strong>(important)&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Breakfast&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Activities&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>You see, i didn&amp;rsquo;t include your phone, or your tv, or your nintendo switch, since this activites are really stimulating,
so if you make this stimulating activities will be really hard to accomplish a less stimulating activity, for example, you are not
going to play videogames and then read a book, it will be extreamly boring and while you are reading you are thinking about playing again,
so that&amp;rsquo;s why organization is extreamly important and the first hour of your day more yet, since this will define your confidence level and mood
for the day, so be smart about it, do this step the night before, so when you wake up you know exactly what you need to do, that will make you
different from everyone else.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="attack">Attack&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After organizing your day it takes action to accomplish what have you promised to do, be &lt;strong>realistic&lt;/strong> please, so that way you will not be
dissapointed about yourself, action is key, just think the momentum and the rhythm you will level up if you accomplish this, don&amp;rsquo;t think much
about it, just go and do it, but remember you are in a war, and in this moment is where the enemy will want to go full gas on his attacks,
the attacks will be:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Distractions (Phone, Videogames, Another activities)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Overthinking (I can&amp;rsquo;t, Will start tomorrow)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lack of purpose (Activities due to accomplish lack purpose)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>False tiredness&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>And you need to be ready to &lt;strong>comeback&lt;/strong> this attacks with something that you know will work, and if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, &lt;strong>make it work&lt;/strong>, that is
what life is about isn&amp;rsquo;t? so be ready and mindful when this happens and prepare your &lt;strong>counter attacks&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="counter-attack">Counter Attack&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Your counter attacks need to be ready before the attacks happens, a warrior doesn&amp;rsquo;t go to war without his sword, so your counter attacks need to be
lock and loaded.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This are mine, and could help your but you know yourself best&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Cold shower&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prepare myself something to eat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go for a walk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Talking to someone for a bit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sing a song&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>These a powerful counter attacks that you can use, just make sure to be ready.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="completing-the-comeback">Completing the comeback&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You complete the comeback by meditating about all you have done, pray to give thanks that you have made it, document everything you made and
be ready for tomorrow, and with time you will grab some high momentum and it will seem easy but &lt;strong>beware&lt;/strong>, that is the time your enemy is
with their guns lock and loaded and you have your guard down, &lt;strong>Don&amp;rsquo;t let that happen&lt;/strong> and if it happens&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="try-again">TRY AGAIN&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Why minimalism is important in your life</title><link>https://saidneder.tech/blog/minimalism/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 23:13:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://saidneder.tech/blog/minimalism/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://saidneder.tech/images/chill-images/curaray.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Why minimalism is important in your life" />&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is my first (and not last) blogpost talking about life advice and my opinions
so just buckle up and enjoy the ride!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-minimalism-in-the-first-place">What is minimalism in the first place?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Is really self-explanatory isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Minimalism is just to live with the bare minimum,
and that goes for everything in life, from your house decorations to your life activities,
and the concept of minimalism really is to achieve simplicity with essential quality,
and that means that is perfect, no need for more or less.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-do-i-need-minimalism-in-my-life">Why do I need minimalism in my life?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s take for example a computer, it has 4 GB of ram and a AMD ryzen 3, which is
really not bad, until we put windows on it&amp;hellip;
Why? Because windows is really a heavy, full-function, full of software you can&amp;rsquo;t get rid of
and don&amp;rsquo;t want in the first place (bloatware), spyware and more creepy stuff that makes windows a really heavy
computer operating system that is really slow on the computer we took for example, since windows on idle
takes aproximately 3-4 GB of ram, but &lt;strong>what if we install a lightweight GNU/Linux distro?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s were the fun begins, you now know that with a lightweight distro that uses aprox. 1 GB of ram
and know you have a lot of ram left to spare, and you become more curious and then you installed arch linux with DWM
for the minimalist setup with only 500 MB of ram usage on idle, and then you notice that you are faster than before on
your windows setup, you use keybindings to navigate faster, and you only have the apps you need.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the perfect example that we can translate to a life example&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a lot of activities like going to the gym, drawing, work or school, cooking classes,
coding sessions and/or reading, without counting social interaction because is an activity we have to work out everyday,
&lt;strong>you will get burned out&lt;/strong> and sadly, never progress on all of your activities, why? because you are not dedicating
enough time to every activity, and that&amp;rsquo;s why you need minimalism, &lt;strong>to progress faster&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="applying-minimalism-day-to-day">Applying minimalism day to day&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>First you need to know your priorities &lt;strong>really well&lt;/strong>, for example a like a lot of things, but
I know deep inside what activities are really important in my life, I will take myself for example
taking by order:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Programming (I want to work on IT and study computer science)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>School (Obligations)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>BJJ (Exercise and a way of live)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Social circle (Family and Friends)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s it for me, we are talking about our activities each day, we need to know our priorities to make the
cut of certain stuff that is taking time from the activities we really need to invest in, for example, I like to cook,
and draw, but they are just &amp;ldquo;hobbies&amp;rdquo; or activities that I enjoy doing but am not going to be a chef or artist, I just
like to do them, that&amp;rsquo;s why I leave space for them in the weekends, because from monday to friday you need to be laser
focus on your principal activites, and those principal activities, that from now on we are going to call them grind, why?
because grind is &lt;strong>an activity where you can work tirelessly and see no return because is leading a bigger purpose.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example myself once again, (is not that am ego-centric or something, I just know me better that anyone) I started
programming as a hobby, two years ago, and now is something that I live and breathe for, this is my spot, my &lt;strong>grind&lt;/strong>,
I have zero percent in return yet, yes I know a lot of stuff, created projects and all, but no one pays me or
obligates me to do so, so why I keep doing it? Because it serves a &lt;strong>major purpose&lt;/strong>, you need to see the big screen boy,
If it ain&amp;rsquo;t about a dream, then it ain&amp;rsquo;t about me as mac miller used to say R.I.P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, now we know our top priority, now what? Time to get to work, This will be your main focus of &lt;strong>every day&lt;/strong>
you have, you wake up and you think about that, you dream about it, the first things that you see in your room are about
it, that&amp;rsquo;s all you got, you have to bet on yourself because if you don&amp;rsquo;t have that, you really got nothing, you see?
You don&amp;rsquo;t have distractions, you don&amp;rsquo;t have other stuff to take out your time, you are dedicated and disciplined, because
you are focused only on one thing, and focus on getting good at it, getting obssesed with the process and soon enough
to enjoy the return of your major labor, that is minimalism, to not have anything besides your grind, so the only thing that
you think about is your grind, concentrate fully on your grind because you got nothing to distract you, and to be patient
and knowing that hard work always pays off!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>